<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Ghani Academy</title><description>Connects to the path of knowledge</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><generator>Ghost 0.8</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 18:09:20 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>Physics Regular course for HSC</title><description>&lt;p&gt;This course contains two classes per week of 1.5 hours duration each. It includes lectures, lab opportunities, practice and exams. Students must not come with the traditional idea of getting good GPA other than having good knowledge on the specific subject. We give priority to student’s curiosity and&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/physics-regular-course-for-hsc/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">1fd251e6-b6a1-403c-9e56-b91757cb20a1</guid><category>Curriculum</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 18:07:31 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This course contains two classes per week of 1.5 hours duration each. It includes lectures, lab opportunities, practice and exams. Students must not come with the traditional idea of getting good GPA other than having good knowledge on the specific subject. We give priority to student’s curiosity and basic conception. Our goal is to make them self-inspired to reach the required level of understanding.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Chemistry Regular course for HSC</title><description>&lt;p&gt;This course is temporarily unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/chemistry-regular-course-for-hsc/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">55f333f4-b935-4d4a-bd62-fb7f6cd37015</guid><category>Curriculum</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 18:06:56 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This course is temporarily unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Mathematics Regular course for HSC</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Mathematics is highly important for understanding scientific process in pure science. So we give utmost priority to make students having clear conception on mathematics. We offer special classes for curious students and also take special care for weak students. This course contains three regular classes per week.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/mathematics-regular-course-for-hsc/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">2edec316-3a5a-44d9-aac8-e06d0e29b6bf</guid><category>Curriculum</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 18:06:23 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Mathematics is highly important for understanding scientific process in pure science. So we give utmost priority to make students having clear conception on mathematics. We offer special classes for curious students and also take special care for weak students. This course contains three regular classes per week.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Physics and Mathematics Conceptual support for SSC and HSC students</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Students should do pre-appointment to join this course. Depending on student's requirements a limited number of classes is scheduled. Student may come individually but if a group of students having similar problems then we prefer to form a batch. Usually the class duration is not less then two hours.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/physics-and-mathematics-conceptual-support-for-ssc-and-hsc-students/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">353f4368-4ad6-4314-a19d-c4ee7c25fa01</guid><category>Curriculum</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 18:05:39 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Students should do pre-appointment to join this course. Depending on student's requirements a limited number of classes is scheduled. Student may come individually but if a group of students having similar problems then we prefer to form a batch. Usually the class duration is not less then two hours.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Junior Secondary Math-Science Course (for class eight)</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Students who are interested to study in science group to the next (SSC) level can get admitted for this course. This is a four month duration program and students will get three lectures weekly. In the three lectures we will try to make them introduced with three major subjects of&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/junior-secondary-math-science-course-for-class-eight-2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">d50eaf0d-e237-4a5c-8c36-b83a6dbcef49</guid><category>Curriculum</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 18:05:07 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Students who are interested to study in science group to the next (SSC) level can get admitted for this course. This is a four month duration program and students will get three lectures weekly. In the three lectures we will try to make them introduced with three major subjects of pure science namely Physics Chemistry and Mathematics. Many of the students are not very fond of mathematics and science. But due to the social demand of science they take it as some boring and necessary subject. In our four months course we try to make an interesting introduction with scientific study. It helps them to better understand and enjoy the later coming up stages of upper level science study. The admission session of this course starts from January 01 and continues till the end of April.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Free conceptual support</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Ghani Academy offers a free opportunity for the learners to discuss their conceptual problems. In this weekly program on each Tuesday (3.00 pm t0 5.00 pm) and Friday(10.00 am to 12.00) students of SSC/HSC, O level and A level may come and discuss their&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/free-conceptual-support/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">f1a41f0d-8943-4d07-9f66-c0c7497fd676</guid><category>Curriculum</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 18:04:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Ghani Academy offers a free opportunity for the learners to discuss their conceptual problems. In this weekly program on each Tuesday (3.00 pm t0 5.00 pm) and Friday(10.00 am to 12.00) students of SSC/HSC, O level and A level may come and discuss their problems related to science and anything of their curiosity related to scientific,philosophical or theological knowledge. Actually it is an open door. Ghani Academy welcomes anyone to come and share their views and ideas. It is appreciated that the person who wishes to come will make a pre-appointment.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Open Discussion Program</title><description>&lt;p&gt;This is a fortnightly program and anyone is invited. Every first,3rd and 5th Thursday of the month [at 6:00pm] people can join to make discussion on their specific topic related to science and knowledge. Any listener can be speaker here and the program will be moderated by Md&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/open-discussion-program/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">7c27ff1e-4265-44a7-91c3-1791ab84fe5c</guid><category>Curriculum</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 18:03:58 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This is a fortnightly program and anyone is invited. Every first,3rd and 5th Thursday of the month [at 6:00pm] people can join to make discussion on their specific topic related to science and knowledge. Any listener can be speaker here and the program will be moderated by Md Anwarul Ghani.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Free Seminar</title><description>&lt;p&gt;We arrange seminar for students to make them more communicative with wider space of science. Only the knowledge of text book is not enough for students thirst to be fulfilled. In the seminar they can come to know more information and latest updates regarding the subject. Usually the subject matter&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/free-seminar/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">a773c47f-98fb-4be8-96e5-2a79b603882e</guid><category>Curriculum</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 18:03:28 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;We arrange seminar for students to make them more communicative with wider space of science. Only the knowledge of text book is not enough for students thirst to be fulfilled. In the seminar they can come to know more information and latest updates regarding the subject. Usually the subject matter of the seminar is selected on the basis of students’ curiosity. We give them option to choose topic for the seminar. Once the topic is fixed it is informed finally to all by sms or e-mail mentioning the date and time of seminar. Before join the seminar students must send confirmation e-mail or sms within a given time deadline and only then they are enlisted as the seminar participants.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Variation of thought</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Variation of thoughts is not any problem if there is honesty and tolerance. Man thinks on the context of circumstances. It is rarely possible to think generally to fit the idea with many variables. It is a natural limitation of man and we have to accept it. Our honesty can&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/variation-of-thought/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">4c011ce1-1576-4f98-ab0f-2bbf64b5e055</guid><category>Articles</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 16:08:42 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Variation of thoughts is not any problem if there is honesty and tolerance. Man thinks on the context of circumstances. It is rarely possible to think generally to fit the idea with many variables. It is a natural limitation of man and we have to accept it. Our honesty can help integrity, tolerance can help opening up the mind to let positive and constructive ideas in... We deserve to have the quality to make communication with others... Possibly one of the most important ways to the path of knowledge is the proper communication with human thought. ..&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Waiting</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The Amir went on: "I do not come here so that our Master should attend to me and converse with me. My purpose in coming is to have the honor of being amongst the company of his servants." For example, just now you were preoccupied and did not show yourself&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/waiting/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">3096c179-6b64-4d0d-9a3c-129555953ae8</guid><category>Articles</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 16:07:37 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The Amir went on: "I do not come here so that our Master should attend to me and converse with me. My purpose in coming is to have the honor of being amongst the company of his servants." For example, just now you were preoccupied and did not show yourself until you had kept me waiting for a long time. This was so I would realize how difficult and disagreeable it is if I keep others waiting when they come to my door and I do not readily admit them. You have made me taste the bitterness of that and have given me a lesson so that I will not act like that with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rumi answered: That's not true. &lt;br&gt;
On the contrary, my keeping you waiting is an expression of utmost loving-kindness. Just as God declares, O my child, I would answer your smallest petition and slightest complaint without delay, if it weren't that the voice of your complaint is so sweet to my ears. My answer lingers unspoken in hopes that you might complain again and again, for the sound of your voice is so sweet to me. &lt;br&gt;
For example, two beggars come to the door of a certain person. One is highly loved and sought after, while the other is not that much liked. The owner of the house says to a slave, Give that hated one a piece of bread quickly and without delay, so he will leave right away. To the other beloved beggar the owner makes promises, saying, The bread is not yet baked. Wait patiently until the bread is properly cooked and baked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Fihi Ma Fihi (Discourse of Jalaluddin Rumi)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Understanding a crow</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I am a crow and I have only one sound 'kraa'. All I say are by repeating this 'kraa'. When your sound resembles to mine it draws my attention and I go near you. It is not for I am fool rather it is for I have the love for&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/understanding-a-crow/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">17d89c40-10c2-40f5-8d9d-537b530b47b5</guid><category>Articles</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 16:06:46 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I am a crow and I have only one sound 'kraa'. All I say are by repeating this 'kraa'. When your sound resembles to mine it draws my attention and I go near you. It is not for I am fool rather it is for I have the love for the sound as it is meaningful to me. You may not understand the meaning but while you utter it, it sounds like my Love is calling me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without being a proper listener you can never know what is said in a say. If you call a crow like the sound it makes, the crow will reply. But you not being a crow or the one to understand it's language will never know what was in his sound 'kraa kraa'. &lt;br&gt;
One thing you must understand that you haven't understood.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Undeletable</title><description>&lt;p&gt;No event ever deletes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if it is the writing of something on dry sand with your finger in a stormy weather.... event is the fact not the time. Time is a wall.. breakable.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/undeletable/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">cb57dd52-d9ba-46e9-8c16-7c55d792025c</guid><category>Articles</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 16:06:22 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;No event ever deletes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if it is the writing of something on dry sand with your finger in a stormy weather.... event is the fact not the time. Time is a wall.. breakable.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Two things we are afraid of</title><description>&lt;p&gt;A sensible human being is afraid of two things. One is death and another is dishonor. Death being an event, which is sure to come anytime in life, can be acceptable and many can be free from its fear. And few can totally accept it as the better conclusion and&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/two-things-we-are-afraid-of/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">d065677b-b63b-4a7a-92d3-61cbfc57f579</guid><category>Articles</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 16:05:52 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;A sensible human being is afraid of two things. One is death and another is dishonor. Death being an event, which is sure to come anytime in life, can be acceptable and many can be free from its fear. And few can totally accept it as the better conclusion and get prepared to welcome it anytime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also it is possible to be free from the willing to gain honor from the society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Human not afraid of death or dishonor is of the extreme kind or the ideal kind. The worst character human being is also free from the fear of death and also he may not care the question of honor. He wants power and he may enjoy torture. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A human of Ideal is not also afraid of death and dishonor while it is for the sake of humanity and Love. He is in Love whereas the worst one is not.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Truth and beauty</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Truth never mixes with false. But in our illusion we see them together in a composition. Sometimes this composition looks like a beauty. This is a description of the fact of illusion. If you search for truth only, you will find Beauty as well. This searching of truth may cause&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/truth-and-beauty/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">4aec91d0-2287-46f6-951d-7d446b5a45e6</guid><category>Articles</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 16:05:20 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Truth never mixes with false. But in our illusion we see them together in a composition. Sometimes this composition looks like a beauty. This is a description of the fact of illusion. If you search for truth only, you will find Beauty as well. This searching of truth may cause you to suffer from pain, besides it gives you the satisfaction to hold on with the suffering. There will be no objection. &lt;br&gt;
But in searching of beauty illusion may come with a nice decorated deceit depending on your expectations. Remember, beauty allures you but truth protects you from the illusion of beauty. Beauty is seeking for your friendship. But truth is always your friend despite you do not love it. So, You be the lover of truth, the friend of truth, only then you can take the proper care of beauty.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Three Questions</title><description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is the only thing you are seeking for? (Only means nothing else you need if you can find that one.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is the only achievement of your life? (If you look at it you just feel you need nothing more.) Do you have any?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you know your destiny?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/three-questions/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6804ba51-5647-4ba0-853e-244a2ba3204e</guid><category>Articles</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 16:04:49 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is the only thing you are seeking for? (Only means nothing else you need if you can find that one.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is the only achievement of your life? (If you look at it you just feel you need nothing more.) Do you have any?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you know your destiny?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The destiny of the life is the event that never we can evade and after the event goes all other events are not under our controls. It is Death. All we know it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only necessity of the life for which we must look for is the thing that is related only to the destiny. And it is purification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the only thing that we can be satisfied with is.. &lt;br&gt;
We have a Creator and He loves us. We are the beloved creation of the Almighty Allah.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>