<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>GHANI Academy</title><description>Connects to the path of knowledge</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><generator>Ghost 0.8</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 17:55:02 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>Variation of thought</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Variation of thoughts is not any problem if there is honesty and tolerance. Man thinks on the context of circumstances. It is rarely possible to think generally to fit the idea with many variables. It is a natural limitation of man and we have to accept it. Our honesty can&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/variation-of-thought/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">4c011ce1-1576-4f98-ab0f-2bbf64b5e055</guid><category>Articles</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 16:08:42 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Variation of thoughts is not any problem if there is honesty and tolerance. Man thinks on the context of circumstances. It is rarely possible to think generally to fit the idea with many variables. It is a natural limitation of man and we have to accept it. Our honesty can help integrity, tolerance can help opening up the mind to let positive and constructive ideas in... We deserve to have the quality to make communication with others... Possibly one of the most important ways to the path of knowledge is the proper communication with human thought. ..&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Waiting</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The Amir went on: "I do not come here so that our Master should attend to me and converse with me. My purpose in coming is to have the honor of being amongst the company of his servants." For example, just now you were preoccupied and did not show yourself&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/waiting/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">3096c179-6b64-4d0d-9a3c-129555953ae8</guid><category>Articles</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 16:07:37 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The Amir went on: "I do not come here so that our Master should attend to me and converse with me. My purpose in coming is to have the honor of being amongst the company of his servants." For example, just now you were preoccupied and did not show yourself until you had kept me waiting for a long time. This was so I would realize how difficult and disagreeable it is if I keep others waiting when they come to my door and I do not readily admit them. You have made me taste the bitterness of that and have given me a lesson so that I will not act like that with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rumi answered: That's not true. &lt;br&gt;
On the contrary, my keeping you waiting is an expression of utmost loving-kindness. Just as God declares, O my child, I would answer your smallest petition and slightest complaint without delay, if it weren't that the voice of your complaint is so sweet to my ears. My answer lingers unspoken in hopes that you might complain again and again, for the sound of your voice is so sweet to me. &lt;br&gt;
For example, two beggars come to the door of a certain person. One is highly loved and sought after, while the other is not that much liked. The owner of the house says to a slave, Give that hated one a piece of bread quickly and without delay, so he will leave right away. To the other beloved beggar the owner makes promises, saying, The bread is not yet baked. Wait patiently until the bread is properly cooked and baked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Fihi Ma Fihi (Discourse of Jalaluddin Rumi)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Understanding a crow</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I am a crow and I have only one sound 'kraa'. All I say are by repeating this 'kraa'. When your sound resembles to mine it draws my attention and I go near you. It is not for I am fool rather it is for I have the love for&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/understanding-a-crow/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">17d89c40-10c2-40f5-8d9d-537b530b47b5</guid><category>Articles</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 16:06:46 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I am a crow and I have only one sound 'kraa'. All I say are by repeating this 'kraa'. When your sound resembles to mine it draws my attention and I go near you. It is not for I am fool rather it is for I have the love for the sound as it is meaningful to me. You may not understand the meaning but while you utter it, it sounds like my Love is calling me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without being a proper listener you can never know what is said in a say. If you call a crow like the sound it makes, the crow will reply. But you not being a crow or the one to understand it's language will never know what was in his sound 'kraa kraa'. &lt;br&gt;
One thing you must understand that you haven't understood.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Undeletable</title><description>&lt;p&gt;No event ever deletes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if it is the writing of something on dry sand with your finger in a stormy weather.... event is the fact not the time. Time is a wall.. breakable.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/undeletable/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">cb57dd52-d9ba-46e9-8c16-7c55d792025c</guid><category>Articles</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 16:06:22 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;No event ever deletes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if it is the writing of something on dry sand with your finger in a stormy weather.... event is the fact not the time. Time is a wall.. breakable.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Two things we are afraid of</title><description>&lt;p&gt;A sensible human being is afraid of two things. One is death and another is dishonor. Death being an event, which is sure to come anytime in life, can be acceptable and many can be free from its fear. And few can totally accept it as the better conclusion and&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/two-things-we-are-afraid-of/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">d065677b-b63b-4a7a-92d3-61cbfc57f579</guid><category>Articles</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 16:05:52 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;A sensible human being is afraid of two things. One is death and another is dishonor. Death being an event, which is sure to come anytime in life, can be acceptable and many can be free from its fear. And few can totally accept it as the better conclusion and get prepared to welcome it anytime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also it is possible to be free from the willing to gain honor from the society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Human not afraid of death or dishonor is of the extreme kind or the ideal kind. The worst character human being is also free from the fear of death and also he may not care the question of honor. He wants power and he may enjoy torture. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A human of Ideal is not also afraid of death and dishonor while it is for the sake of humanity and Love. He is in Love whereas the worst one is not.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Truth and beauty</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Truth never mixes with false. But in our illusion we see them together in a composition. Sometimes this composition looks like a beauty. This is a description of the fact of illusion. If you search for truth only, you will find Beauty as well. This searching of truth may cause&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/truth-and-beauty/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">4aec91d0-2287-46f6-951d-7d446b5a45e6</guid><category>Articles</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 16:05:20 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Truth never mixes with false. But in our illusion we see them together in a composition. Sometimes this composition looks like a beauty. This is a description of the fact of illusion. If you search for truth only, you will find Beauty as well. This searching of truth may cause you to suffer from pain, besides it gives you the satisfaction to hold on with the suffering. There will be no objection. &lt;br&gt;
But in searching of beauty illusion may come with a nice decorated deceit depending on your expectations. Remember, beauty allures you but truth protects you from the illusion of beauty. Beauty is seeking for your friendship. But truth is always your friend despite you do not love it. So, You be the lover of truth, the friend of truth, only then you can take the proper care of beauty.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Three Questions</title><description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is the only thing you are seeking for? (Only means nothing else you need if you can find that one.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is the only achievement of your life? (If you look at it you just feel you need nothing more.) Do you have any?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you know your destiny?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/three-questions/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6804ba51-5647-4ba0-853e-244a2ba3204e</guid><category>Articles</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 16:04:49 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is the only thing you are seeking for? (Only means nothing else you need if you can find that one.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is the only achievement of your life? (If you look at it you just feel you need nothing more.) Do you have any?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you know your destiny?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The destiny of the life is the event that never we can evade and after the event goes all other events are not under our controls. It is Death. All we know it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only necessity of the life for which we must look for is the thing that is related only to the destiny. And it is purification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the only thing that we can be satisfied with is.. &lt;br&gt;
We have a Creator and He loves us. We are the beloved creation of the Almighty Allah.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Read hot coal</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Day will come when it will be so difficult to keep faith that it will be just like holding a red hot coal in your hand. &lt;br&gt;
Yes..now we see the days.. no doubt. &lt;br&gt;
But once if you can hold it and have the taste of the pain.. you will&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/read-hot-coal/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">d58ae5ac-669c-44b5-b31b-d9a5b57553fd</guid><category>Articles</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 16:04:09 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Day will come when it will be so difficult to keep faith that it will be just like holding a red hot coal in your hand. &lt;br&gt;
Yes..now we see the days.. no doubt. &lt;br&gt;
But once if you can hold it and have the taste of the pain.. you will even try to burn your heart with its fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trials of composing Islam in different fashions are available in this so called civilized society. But Islam is not to be composed. You just hold the rope of Islam. It exists in its divineness. We cant imagine its amazing beauty unless we are in the reality of its practicing. &lt;br&gt;
Save muslims..not Islam. You are the first Muslim to be saved. Get out form the illusive attraction of this civilization. The red hot coal can help you to burn your wishes. &lt;br&gt;
May Allah help us.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Prayer that was Answered</title><description>&lt;p&gt;A tale from Mathnawi of Mawlana Jalaluddin Rumi&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A CERTAIN man one night was crying 'Allah!' till his lips were becoming sweet with the mention of his name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;'Why now, chatterbox,' said the Devil, 'where is the answer "Here am I" to all this "Allah" of yours? Not&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/prayer-that-was-answered/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">493d0068-7f80-4ea1-b0d3-c62aa30fc789</guid><category>Articles</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 16:03:38 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;A tale from Mathnawi of Mawlana Jalaluddin Rumi&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A CERTAIN man one night was crying 'Allah!' till his lips were becoming sweet with the mention of his name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;'Why now, chatterbox,' said the Devil, 'where is the answer "Here am I" to all this "Allah" of yours? Not one answer is coming from the Throne: how long will your grimly go on crying "Allah"?'&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man became broken-hearted, and laid down his head to sleep. &lt;br&gt;
He saw in a dream mystic Khazir. [Khazir was a mysterious guide who first appears in Koran XVIII:64 (not named, but identified by the commentators as 'one of Our servants unto whom We had given mercy from Us, and We had taught him knowledge proceeding from Us') as accompanying Moses and doing strange things. The Sufis took him as the exempler of the Shaikh who requires absolute and unquestioning obedience of the disciple. all in a green garden.] &lt;br&gt;
'Look now,' Khazir called, 'why have you desisted from the mention of God? How is it you repent of having called upon Him?'&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;'No answering "Here am I" is coming to me,' the man replied, 'and I therefore fear that I may be refused from His door.'&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Khazir answered, 'Your cry of "Allah" (God says) is itself My "Here am I"; your pleading and agony and fervour is My messenger. All your twistings and turnings to come to Me were My drawing you that set free your feet. Your fear and love are the lasso to catch My grace. Under each "Allah" of yours whispers many a "Here am I".&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Past Present Future</title><description>&lt;p&gt;You live in present right? What is the length of present? One second? &lt;br&gt;
No. Less than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Past is in our memory and the future is in the expectation and in the &lt;br&gt;
results of what we did and do in past and present. With all these we live &lt;br&gt;
in a&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/past-present-future/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">b8a185f4-4270-4410-9f21-ffad9818e3ae</guid><category>Articles</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 16:03:06 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;You live in present right? What is the length of present? One second? &lt;br&gt;
No. Less than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Past is in our memory and the future is in the expectation and in the &lt;br&gt;
results of what we did and do in past and present. With all these we live &lt;br&gt;
in a single (Physically dimensionless) moment which is called &lt;br&gt;
the reality of our existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We say past present future. But our existence in the present stands as the divider. Existence is the reality that we must accept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are alive in a single moment. &lt;br&gt;
Like we are always in a compartment. &lt;br&gt;
Changes. &lt;br&gt;
Unidirectional trip. &lt;br&gt;
Two doors. &lt;br&gt;
One transparent and is prohibited to pass. &lt;br&gt;
Another one is opened but not possible to see which is behind. &lt;br&gt;
So many false drawings on the door. &lt;br&gt;
But all we know the destiny. &lt;br&gt;
Our hope is to reach the phase of the Clarity. &lt;br&gt;
Our destiny is a meeting. &lt;br&gt;
A Holy Meeting. &lt;br&gt;
This is what we are waiting for.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Talking Parrot</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Think aobut the parrot! &lt;br&gt;
When it was singing its words the owner found it as usless noise and taught it his meaningful words. Once it learns to utter the words of its owner... &lt;br&gt;
he says, 'O my parrot can talk now!' &lt;br&gt;
But the fact is, it has forgotten to&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/talking-parrot/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">f804a26c-2f32-41b2-8d35-0aa1fe877b9e</guid><category>Articles</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 16:01:43 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Think aobut the parrot! &lt;br&gt;
When it was singing its words the owner found it as usless noise and taught it his meaningful words. Once it learns to utter the words of its owner... &lt;br&gt;
he says, 'O my parrot can talk now!' &lt;br&gt;
But the fact is, it has forgotten to speak its own! &lt;br&gt;
Its soul always cry its own. &lt;br&gt;
We are not parrots. We dont want to be. Our communication with wordily communicates must not be like the above allegory. &lt;br&gt;
Dont make me talk like you and i wont like you to talk like me. As we feel unlike so word helps a little. There is a communication of silent prayer that makes unlike like.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Pain</title><description>&lt;p&gt;It is not like what I want, it is what I see. &lt;br&gt;
My peace is if I can accept it. &lt;br&gt;
And pain is if I can't. &lt;br&gt;
And mostly I can. &lt;br&gt;
When I was unable to, there was a pain. &lt;br&gt;
But now the pain is like a friend. &lt;br&gt;
It helps me&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/pain/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">d5f2ea29-b648-4b4a-b38f-31c4004cbc3d</guid><category>Articles</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 16:01:12 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;It is not like what I want, it is what I see. &lt;br&gt;
My peace is if I can accept it. &lt;br&gt;
And pain is if I can't. &lt;br&gt;
And mostly I can. &lt;br&gt;
When I was unable to, there was a pain. &lt;br&gt;
But now the pain is like a friend. &lt;br&gt;
It helps me to understand that I am not understanding.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>O Lovers</title><description>&lt;p&gt;When Love appears the reason disappears. &lt;br&gt;
And once that the reason is gone it is of no use. &lt;br&gt;
The Reason is one of the doors but Love is the Palace. &lt;br&gt;
O lovers you are inside a palace. &lt;br&gt;
Don't look back to the door. Let the door be closed. &lt;br&gt;
Be trapped&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/o-lovers/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">c05558e6-faa7-49bf-b3ab-7bdf3dd4d0e6</guid><category>Articles</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 16:00:41 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;When Love appears the reason disappears. &lt;br&gt;
And once that the reason is gone it is of no use. &lt;br&gt;
The Reason is one of the doors but Love is the Palace. &lt;br&gt;
O lovers you are inside a palace. &lt;br&gt;
Don't look back to the door. Let the door be closed. &lt;br&gt;
Be trapped in love. See the beauty inside it. Do you see the palace destroyed? Listen to the cry of love from each and every brick of the palace. Why do you stop here? You have the love to reconstruct the palace. Don't worry!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the lovers are sensitive and no lover is blind. No way, because love itself is a light. If you have the light of love no light can ever let you see things with more clarity. If you are truly in Love of a creation how is it possible to be unaware of The Creator?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love is the ultimate phase of knowing. If the identity of your beloved is the creation of The Loving Creator then you be right at a stage before loving The Creator. But remember, you are in Love and you are the beloved. From your beloved for what you seek? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are the fruit of love. You have the seed inside. Keep the seed with care because you are a conveyer of love.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Need</title><description>&lt;p&gt;How can you be sure that it is your need? &lt;br&gt;
Care your soul. Too much caring your body causes your soul to be weakened...to die. When the rider is to go towards the destiny what good of the horse if the rider is just sleeping on it not caring&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/need/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">8a28785a-9b1d-4acc-9571-ffca03037e4b</guid><category>Articles</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 16:00:05 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;How can you be sure that it is your need? &lt;br&gt;
Care your soul. Too much caring your body causes your soul to be weakened...to die. When the rider is to go towards the destiny what good of the horse if the rider is just sleeping on it not caring where it goes? You must have the control of your horse when you are riding on it. Don't let it to be just a runner. You may fall down from it and you will die before reaching the destiny. So this is the right time to wake up. Take care of your soul. &lt;br&gt;
You are just in time. Important are the words. You see if the words are for you. &lt;br&gt;
We are naturally in a path of purification. Sometimes we know and sometimes we know not. Not any of our phase is permanent unless we are purified. Our pains proof that this is not the ultimate phase. &lt;br&gt;
You may suffer from a disease knowing and without knowing that the disease is in your body. But the doctor knows. So he is telling you to be careful even when you are not in the pain. Because he knows that someday it will come. When you are the sufferer it is eventual to look for a doctor. There is a doctor in you who will take you to the real doctor. You just need to activate the doctor in you. This is the only thing you are to do. Give your doctor the freedom to look for a true doctor. &lt;br&gt;
You are already helped. You were never helpless. &lt;br&gt;
Troubles come for two reasons. Either it is your punishment or it is that you are in the process and overcoming it you will be honored as a winner of examination. Both are good for you. Punishments are for Allah wants your purification through it and examination is only for the selected peoples who will be given better responsibilities. It is an honor it is a Love. Allah is hoping that you will be purified through the punishment. It is also for Love. He wants you to know the reality of pain when purity impurity mixes. Love is pure. When pure and impure mixes, it makes the pain. Pain purifies you. Are you still in the pain? If you are, it means both are in you now living together, Love and impurity. If either of that two disappears, you will feel no pain. &lt;br&gt;
Ultimately the creation is Loved.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>In the same Caravan</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Human life is a path of purification. Path of purification is the path of knowledge. One who is a traveler and knows his path can attain the destiny and a one who is a traveler but not knowing his path also attains. It happens when they are in the same&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/in-the-same-caravan/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">ad384806-7b2e-482d-8907-f798a25662ea</guid><category>Articles</category><dc:creator>Anwarul Ghani</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 15:59:22 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Human life is a path of purification. Path of purification is the path of knowledge. One who is a traveler and knows his path can attain the destiny and a one who is a traveler but not knowing his path also attains. It happens when they are in the same caravan. What is the difference here?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try to think that we all are in the same caravan of purification. But the stages are not coming to all of us with the same pleasure and troubles. Let us share the pleasure and let us help each other during the troubles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you think that being a reader of books and having skills of writing expressions you are in the path of knowledge but not they are who are not in touch? It is true that you can't ensure the process for all. Actually this process is not necessary for all but how can you imagine that the One Who made it for all made it so that you the people are to taste it only? One whom you are ignoring is not ignored. One whom you honor may not be honored. Love is the connection. It is your sincere desire that can communicate.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>